studyusa.com 2019-10-16

# 

## Privacy Policy

#### Effective Date: May 25, 2018

Study in the USA, Inc. ("StudyUSA," "us," "we," or "our") have updated our Privacy Policy to help you (the individual who uses this website, features, and services, or accesses available information, or engages directly by email or social media) understand what our information practices are with respect to the collection, use, and disclosure of information we collect from you through our web application, and other media that link to this Privacy Policy. We respect your privacy and security, and we are committed to fair practices that protect the information you share with us. 

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your Personal Information, then please contact us at privacy@studyusa.com.

Study in the USA, Inc. is a Washington corporation with a principal place of business at 100 S King St #425, Seattle, WA 98104. If you reside or are in the European Economic Area ("EEA") StudyUSA is the data controller of all Personally Identifiable Information (as defined below) and of certain Personally Identifiable Information collected from third parties, as set out in this Privacy Policy.

### What Information this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers information we collect from you through our website. Some of our website functionality can be used without revealing any Personally Identifiable Information, though for some features or services Personally Identifiable Information is required. To access certain features and benefits on our Site, you may need to submit, or we may collect, “Personally Identifiable Information” (i.e., information that can be used to identify you). Personally Identifiable Information can include information such as your name and email address, among other things. You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to StudyUSA. Inaccurate information may affect your ability to use the Site, the information you receive when using the Site, and our ability to contact you. For example, your email address should be kept current because that is one of the primary manners in which we communicate with you. 

### Information from persons under the age of 18

If you are under age 13, please do not attempt to register for StudyUSA or provide any Personally Identifiable Information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personally Identifiable Information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 13, please contact us. We strongly recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet and we encourage parents to teach their children about safe internet use practices. 

### What You Agree to by Using Our Site

Please understand that by submitting any Personally Identifiable Information to us, you consent and agree that we may collect, use and disclose such Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and as permitted or required by law. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personally Identifiable Information, we may not be able to provide you with the services that can be offered on our Site. 

### What Information We Collect

**Information relating to your use of our Site.** When users come to our Site, we may track, collect and aggregate information indicating, among other things, which pages of our Site were visited, the order in which they were visited, when they were visited, and which hyperlinks were "clicked." We also collect information from the URLs from which you linked to our Site. Collecting such information may involve logging the IP address, operating system and browser software used by each user of the Site. We may be able to determine from an IP address a user’s Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. Study in the USA does use cookies (small files put on your computer). 

**Partner sites.** Partner may collect nonfinancial individual level user data regarding the individual’s use of that partner site while engaged with such related activities, and the partner sites may share that data with StudyUSA for the purpose of improving StudyUSA’s services, the partner site’s services, and the individual’s Site experience. This data includes information such as the amount of time spent on the partner site and pages viewed.

### How We Use the Information

**Personally Identifiable Information provided directly by you.** We collect Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to us when you register for an account, update or change information for your account, sign-up for email updates, send us email messages, and/or use other services on our Site. We may use the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to respond to your questions, send you updates, and send you email messages about Site maintenance or updates. 

**Account Registration.** When you sign up on StudyUSA's student login, you provide us with your name, email, gender, and birth date ("Personally Identifiable Information"). You will be able to add a picture of yourself. Once you register you can provide other information about yourself by connecting with, for example, your current city, activities, school size, and other preferences. You can also provide Personally Identifiable Information about yourself. We collect and store your Personally Identifiable Information, if you voluntarily enter it. This information is forwarded to our email service provider and passed on to the schools or services you identify (or sometimes to a third-party partner or vendor under contract with a school or service you identify) in an email generated by our email service provider, so that the schools, services or third-party partners or vendors may contact you with more information. In addition, we use this information to match you with schools based on various factors including preferences and TOEFL practice scores. We also share this information with our email service provider for the purpose of delivering a transaction confirmation to you. Other Personally Identifiable Information may be shared as required to fulfill your information request or to notify you when a third party provides a product or service that we feel may be of interest to you. We may also share your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties in order that they may send you information about their products or services when you have expressly consented to our doing so, such as by clicking a checkbox on the Website. Use of your Personally Identifiable Information by a school, service or third party is governed by such school's service's or third party's privacy policy. We will not share your Personally Identifiable Information with anyone except as provided in this privacy policy. 

**Communications with StudyUSA.** StudyUSA may offer you the ability to receive updates either via email or by posting on portions of the Site only accessible to registered users. To subscribe to these services, you may be required to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information such as your name and email address. We use Personally Identifiable Information collected when you sign-up for our various email or update services to send you the messages in connection with the Site. We may also archive this information and/or use it for future communications with you, where we are legally entitled to do so. 

**Information relating to your use of our Site.** We use information relating to your use of the Site to build higher quality, more useful services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our users, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of our Site. We may also use this information to ensure the security of our services and the Site. 

**Personally Identifiable Information provided directly by you or via third parties.** Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, StudyUSA will not disclose any of your Personally Identifiable Information. In addition to the other uses set forth in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose and otherwise use Personally Identifiable Information as described below. 

**Identity Verification.** For services that require identity verification, we use the Personally Identifiable Information that we collect for verifying your identity, and for authenticating that submissions made on the Site were made by you. This service may be provided through a third-party identity verification vendor. 

**Communications with Study in the USA Business Partners.** We may share your Personally Identifiable Information with school partners and other business partners of StudyUSA so that these partners may share information about their products and services that may be of interest to you where we are legally entitled to do so. Different schools and services have different methods of following up with student information requests. Some will send brochures in the mail, while others will reply via email or try to contact individuals by telephone. By using our service to request information from schools or services, you are giving permission to the schools or services (or their partners or vendors) to contact you, using the method of their choice, to fulfill your information request. 

**Government Authorities, Legal Rights and Actions.** StudyUSA may share your Personally Identifiable Information with various government authorities in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights or to protect our property; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. We also may share your Personally Identifiable Information when we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of StudyUSA, the Site, our users, customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Use and other agreements. 

**Links to other websites.** Our Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

**Retention of Personally Identifiable Information.** We keep your Personally Identifiable Information for no longer than necessary for the purposes for which the Personally Identifiable Information is processed. The length of time we retain Personally Identifiable Information for depends on the purposes for which we collect and use it and/or as required to comply with applicable laws and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights. 

### Confidentiality & Security of Personally Identifiable Information

We consider the confidentiality and security of your information to be of the utmost importance. We will use industry standard physical, technical and administrative security measures to keep your Personally Identifiable Information confidential and secure and will not share it with third parties, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, or unless such disclosure is necessary in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others, as permitted by applicable law. Because the Internet is not a 100% secure environment we cannot guarantee the security of Personally Identifiable Information, and there is some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way to circumvent our security systems or that transmission of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that e-mail communications are typically not encrypted and should not be considered secure. 

### Updating or Deleting Your Personally Identifiable Information 

You have certain rights in relation to your Personally Identifiable Information. You can access your Personally Identifiable Information and confirm that it remains correct and up-to-date or choose whether or not you wish to receive material from us or some of our partners by logging into the Site and visiting your Student page. 

If you would like further information in relation to your rights or would like to exercise any of them, you may also contact us via privacy@studyusa.com. If you reside or are located in the EEA, you have the right to request that we: 

  * provide access to any Personally Identifiable Information we hold about you;
  * prevent the processing of your Personally Identifiable Information for direct-marketing purposes; 
  * update any Personally Identifiable Information which is out of date or incorrect;
  * delete any Personally Identifiable Information which we are holding about you;
  * restrict the way that we process your Personally Identifiable Information;
  * provide your Personally Identifiable Information to a third-party provider of services; or
  * provide you with a copy of any Personally Identifiable Information which we hold about you.

We try to answer every email promptly where possible and provide our response within the time period stated by applicable law. Keep in mind, however, that there will be residual information that will remain within our databases, access logs and other records, which may or may not contain your Personally Identifiable Information. Please also note that certain Personally Identifiable Information may be exempt from such requests in certain circumstances, which may include if we need to keep processing your Personally Identifiable Information to comply with a legal obligation. When you email us with a request, we may ask that you provide us with information necessary to confirm your identity. 

### How to Contact Us

If you have any privacy-related questions, suggestions, or unresolved problems, you may contact us by sending a message to privacy@studyusa.com or write to us at: 

Study in the USA, Inc.  
100 S King St #425  
Seattle, WA 98104  

### Privacy Policy Changes

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. You agree to this Privacy Policy, and any changes to the same, by visiting this Website. Therefore, we encourage you to review changes to our privacy policy every time you visit this Website.
